<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Films on Tom Bishop</title>
    <link>/films/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Films on Tom Bishop</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 09 Sep 2018 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/films/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>9 September 18</title>
      <link>/films/9-sep-18/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 09 Sep 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/films/9-sep-18/</guid>
      <description>I, TonyaDRAMA  PICK OF THE WEEK  Tom : I, Tonya is based on the true story of US figure skater Tonya Harding who was implicated in the decapacitating assault of competing US figure skater Nancy Kerrigan.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>2 - September</title>
      <link>/films/2-september-edition/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 02 Sep 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/films/2-september-edition/</guid>
      <description>Mission: Impossible Fallout Hannah:  PICK OF THE WEEK  I’ve never loved the Mission Impossible franchise. It falls into the same basket as James Bond for me - action that takes itself too seriously. But this one was great.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>29 - July</title>
      <link>/films/29-july-edition/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 29 Jul 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/films/29-july-edition/</guid>
      <description>Super Dark Times Tom:  PICK OF THE WEEK  I really enjoyed this one. It’s one of those films (and there’s a few of them) that follow a group of kids or teenagers through some confronting or harrowing event.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>15 - July</title>
      <link>/films/15-july-edition/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 15 Jul 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/films/15-july-edition/</guid>
      <description>The Equalizer Hannah:  PICK OF THE WEEK  This has got to be my favourite film genre. Tough-but-moral guy, out for revenge with a skill set that can not be matched. This came out in 2014 and I am not sure how we missed it then but I’m now very excited for the second one.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>1 - July</title>
      <link>/films/1-july-edition/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Jul 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/films/1-july-edition/</guid>
      <description>Bone Tomahawk Hannah:  PICK OF THE WEEK  We watched Bone Tomahawk because it was directed by S. Craig Zahler, the guy who did Brawl in Cell Block 99 (see the 5 - May Review), and we were not disappointed.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>23 - June</title>
      <link>/films/23-june-edition/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 23 Jun 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/films/23-june-edition/</guid>
      <description>Game Night Hannah:  PICK OF THE WEEK  Game Night was surprisingly good. The trailer made it out to be one those generic comedies filled with exaggerated caricatures, physical humour and outlandish awkward situations (think Sex Tape and Bad Teacher), but it was definitely better than that.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>16 - June</title>
      <link>/films/16-june-edition/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 16 Jun 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/films/16-june-edition/</guid>
      <description>Hereditary Tom:  PICK OF THE WEEK  Being our favourite genre Hannah and I watch a lot of horror movies so we’re quite desensitized. But this film was straight scary. So scary in fact that (and this is no joke) a woman in our cinema legitimately had a panic attack during the film’s climax; she was wailing and hyperventilating in the cinema, it was chaos.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>9 - June</title>
      <link>/films/9-june-edition/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 09 Jun 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/films/9-june-edition/</guid>
      <description>mother! Hannah:  PICK OF THE WEEK  The fact that this movie title conspicuously begins with a lowercase letter already hints at the weirdness that follows. It has a great cast – J-law, Jarvier Bardem, Michelle Pfeiffer (man that is a strange surname to spell) and Ed Harris, who all do a killer job.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>28 - May</title>
      <link>/films/28-may-edition/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 28 May 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/films/28-may-edition/</guid>
      <description>Whiplash Hannah:  PICK OF THE WEEK  Whiplash was great and intense. I was frustrated throughout and I hated both of the main characters, but I’m pretty sure that was intentional. It’s a story of a talented young musician and his ruthless and abusive teacher.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>21 - May</title>
      <link>/films/21-may-edition/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 21 May 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/films/21-may-edition/</guid>
      <description>Three Billboards Outside Ebbing, Missouri Hannah:  PICK OF THE WEEK  Three Billboards Outside Ebbing, Missouri has a really long title and a 2 hour run time and I didn’t want it to end. After watching it we found out it was directed by Martin McDonagh and we thought who is that?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>5 - May</title>
      <link>/films/5-may-edition/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 05 May 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/films/5-may-edition/</guid>
      <description>The Ritual Tom:  The Ritual starts off on the PERFECT note. A bunch of guys are ominously planning an off-the-beaten track holiday followed by a completely unexpected, and ultra-realistic, liquor store robbery that leaves one character dead and the other guilt-stricken.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>21 - April</title>
      <link>/films/21-april-edition/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 21 Apr 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/films/21-april-edition/</guid>
      <description>Flatliners Hannah:  The genre mash of science fiction and horror is one of my favourites, but Flatliners is an example of what happens when both are done badly. The movie’s central theme is about past sins and repentance, so you would think the goal is to see the characters as good humans who have made mistakes right?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>12 April 18</title>
      <link>/films/12-apr-18/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Apr 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/films/12-apr-18/</guid>
      <description>Ingrid Goes WestCOMEDY   Tom : I really don’t know what to say about this movie. We literally had to stop it half way through (and pick it up a few days later) because it was so excruciatingly cringe inducing.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>