<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Tom Bishop</title>
    <link>/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Tom Bishop</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 03 Dec 2018 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>3 December 18</title>
      <link>/films/3-dec-18/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 Dec 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/films/3-dec-18/</guid>
      <description>Death Of StalinCOMEDY  PICK OF THE WEEK  Tom : Death Of Stalin is a satirical comedy about dicatorship and the tyrannical rule of Joseph Stalin during the soviet union. Steve Buschemi (Nikita Krushchev) leads a group of excellent performances by the 5-6 senior USSR officials jockeying for power after Stalin&amp;#39;s death.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hannabishy Films</title>
      <link>/shiny/hannabishy-films/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 15 Nov 2018 12:26:46 +1000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/shiny/hannabishy-films/</guid>
      <description>Details Hannabishy Films is a simple shiny app using the flexdashboard implementation. It reads in the YAML config for each of Hannah and my film reviews (can be read through the films tab above) and presents them together in a single place for you to easily select the best film to watch tonight!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>12 November 18</title>
      <link>/films/12-nov-18/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Nov 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/films/12-nov-18/</guid>
      <description>Ready Player OneSCI-FI  PICK OF THE WEEK  Tom : Steven Spielberg&amp;#39;s blockbuster Ready Player One is set in a dystopian 2045 where humans spend most of their time living in a VR system called OASIS.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>7 October 18</title>
      <link>/films/7-oct-18/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 07 Oct 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/films/7-oct-18/</guid>
      <description>Sweet VirginiaDRAMA  PICK OF THE WEEK  Tom : Christopher Abbott plays Elwood, a contract killer, hired in a small Alaskan town by a woman who wants to kill her husband for financial reasons.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>SMOOVE</title>
      <link>/shiny/smoove/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 05 Oct 2018 12:26:46 +1000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/shiny/smoove/</guid>
      <description>Details SMOOVE uses NBA stats API data to build a player evaluation, performance and trend dashboard. Built to hopefully replace my 10-20 daily basketball reference searches and fantasy research on yahoo fantasy basketball; SMOOVE is more compact and visual than its counterparts. V1 focusses on investigations of:
 Intra (within) season trends Inter (across) season trends (ie career trajectory) Ranking relative to player peers (based on positions, and starting status)  Hopefully will spend effort on building out more views, time permitting.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>23 September 18</title>
      <link>/films/23-sep-18/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 23 Sep 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/films/23-sep-18/</guid>
      <description>Tragedy GirlsHORROR  PICK OF THE WEEK  Tom : Sadie and McKayla are high school aged best friends who run a true crime blog called &amp;#39;Tradgedy Girls&amp;#39;. Enthusiasts of crime and serial murder they portray themselves as keen observers of their town’s spree of killings; however, they end up becoming more involved than the viewer initially expects.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>9 September 18</title>
      <link>/films/9-sep-18/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 09 Sep 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/films/9-sep-18/</guid>
      <description>I, TonyaDRAMA  PICK OF THE WEEK  Tom : I, Tonya is based on the true story of US figure skater Tonya Harding who was implicated in the decapacitating assault of competing US figure skater Nancy Kerrigan.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>2 September 18</title>
      <link>/films/2-september-18/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 02 Sep 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/films/2-september-18/</guid>
      <description>Mission Impossible: FalloutACTION  PICK OF THE WEEK  Hannah : I&amp;#39;ve never loved the Mission Impossible franchise. It falls into the same basket as James Bond for me - action that takes itself too seriously.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>29 July 18</title>
      <link>/films/29-july-18/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 29 Jul 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/films/29-july-18/</guid>
      <description>Super Dark TimesTHRILLER  PICK OF THE WEEK  Tom : I really enjoyed this one. It&amp;#39;s one of those films (and there&amp;#39;s a few of them) that follow a group of kids or teenagers through some confronting or harrowing event.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>15 July 18</title>
      <link>/films/15-july-18/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 15 Jul 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/films/15-july-18/</guid>
      <description>The EqualizerACTION  PICK OF THE WEEK  Hannah : This has got to be my favourite film genre. Tough-but-moral guy, out for revenge with a skill set that can not be matched. This came out in 2014 and I am not sure how we missed it then but I’m now very excited for the second one.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>1 July 18</title>
      <link>/films/1-july-18/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Jul 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/films/1-july-18/</guid>
      <description>Bone TomahawkACTION  PICK OF THE WEEK  Hannah : We watched Bone Tomahawk because it was directed by S. Craig Zahler, the guy who did Brawl in Cell Block 99 (see the 5 - May Review), and we were not disappointed.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>23 June 18</title>
      <link>/films/23-june-18/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 23 Jun 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/films/23-june-18/</guid>
      <description>Game NightCOMEDY  PICK OF THE WEEK  Hannah : Game Night was surprisingly good. The trailer made it out to be one those generic comedies filled with exaggerated caricatures, physical humour and outlandish awkward situations (think Sex Tape and Bad Teacher), but it was definitely better than that.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>16 June 18</title>
      <link>/films/16-june-18/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 16 Jun 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/films/16-june-18/</guid>
      <description>HereditaryHORROR  PICK OF THE WEEK  Tom : Being our favourite genre Hannah and I watch a lot of horror movies so we’re quite desensitized. But this film was straight scary. So scary in fact that (and this is no joke) a woman in our cinema legitimately had a panic attack during the film’s climax; she was wailing and hyperventilating in the cinema, it was chaos.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>9 June 18</title>
      <link>/films/9-june-18/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 09 Jun 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/films/9-june-18/</guid>
      <description>mother!DRAMA  PICK OF THE WEEK  Hannah : The fact that this movie title conspicuously begins with a lowercase letter already hints at the weirdness that follows. It has a great cast – J-law, Jarvier Bardem, Michelle Pfeiffer (man that is a strange surname to spell) and Ed Harris, who all do a killer job.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>28 May 18</title>
      <link>/films/28-may-18/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 28 May 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/films/28-may-18/</guid>
      <description>WhiplashDRAMA  PICK OF THE WEEK  Hannah : Whiplash was great and intense. I was frustrated throughout and I hated both of the main characters, but I’m pretty sure that was intentional. It’s a story of a talented young musician and his ruthless and abusive teacher.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>21 May 18</title>
      <link>/films/21-may-18/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 21 May 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/films/21-may-18/</guid>
      <description>Three Billboards Outside Ebbing, MissouriDRAMA  PICK OF THE WEEK  Hannah : Three Billboards Outside Ebbing, Missouri has a really long title and a 2 hour run time and I didn’t want it to end.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>5 May 18</title>
      <link>/films/5-may-18/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 05 May 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/films/5-may-18/</guid>
      <description>The RitualHORROR   Tom : The Ritual starts off on the PERFECT note. A bunch of guys are ominously planning an off-the-beaten track holiday followed by a completely unexpected, and ultra-realistic, liquor store robbery that leaves one character dead and the other guilt-stricken.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>21 April 18</title>
      <link>/films/21-apr-18/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 21 Apr 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/films/21-apr-18/</guid>
      <description>FlatlinersSCI-FI   Hannah : The genre mash of science fiction and horror is one of my favourites, but Flatliners is an example of what happens when both are done badly. The movie’s central theme is about past sins and repentance, so you would think the goal is to see the characters as good humans who have made mistakes right?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>12 April 18</title>
      <link>/films/12-apr-18/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Apr 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/films/12-apr-18/</guid>
      <description>Ingrid Goes WestCOMEDY   Tom : I really don’t know what to say about this movie. We literally had to stop it half way through (and pick it up a few days later) because it was so excruciatingly cringe inducing.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Adding Interactivity to Static Rmarkdown Documents</title>
      <link>/lab/adding-rmarkdown-interactivity/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 Nov 2017 20:40:30 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/lab/adding-rmarkdown-interactivity/</guid>
      <description>OverviewAdding interactivity to data analytics outputs is a great tool to have in your toolkit.
As an R User you have a few major output formats to choose from. However, it’s not immediately obvious how much interactivity you can embed within each format.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Using Shinydashboard Elements in Shiny</title>
      <link>/lab/shinydashboard-elements/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 Nov 2017 20:40:09 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/lab/shinydashboard-elements/</guid>
      <description>Shinydashboard is built off the Bootstrap Admin LTE theme. It contains some cool elements (value/info boxes) that look pretty snazzy in a shiny dashboard. To use any of these elements (due to the differences in app creation syntax) within your regular shiny app you can’t just load the shinydashboard package.
You’ll just need to grab a couple of CSS files from the shinydashboard package source code.
Navigate to your [R Home]/library/shinydashboard/ and grab:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Bulletin Edition 1 with Source</title>
      <link>/lab/bulletin-edition-1-with-source/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 Nov 2017 20:40:04 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/lab/bulletin-edition-1-with-source/</guid>
      <description>Nah but actually The Intern was ok.

Much analysis has been completed regarding the performing peak of athletes and sportspeople. Statistically, swimmers peak at around 24, marathon runners between 30-31, gymnasts at a mere 18, NBA players generally peak between 26-29, professional hockey players between 27-28, and chess players at 30-35.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>R Markdown Test</title>
      <link>/lab/r-markdown-test/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 Nov 2017 20:38:16 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/lab/r-markdown-test/</guid>
      <description>OverviewHey. Just testing the Rmd funcitonality of this page. Maybe I’m interested in the BMI of human star wars characters. Maybe. Let’s see how this goes:
library(dplyr)library(ggplot2)starwars %&amp;gt;%filter(species == &amp;quot;Human&amp;quot;) %&amp;gt;%ggplot(aes(y=height, x=mass, colour=species)) +geom_point() +geom_smooth() +theme_bw() +ggtitle(&amp;quot;Starwars BMI&amp;quot;)</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>HHTL</title>
      <link>/shiny/hhtl/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 Oct 2017 09:21:46 +1000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/shiny/hhtl/</guid>
      <description> Details Hannah&amp;rsquo;s History Time Line (HHTL) is a minimalist shiny app I built to help my wife learn and retain history. The app contains a simple timevis timeline widget with functionality to add and edit events. Technically the app includes:
 A googlesheets backend using the googlesheets package UI elements from shinyWidgets and shiny.semantic Some extra interactivity with shinyjs  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Prime of Their Life: The Halflife of Acting Talent</title>
      <link>/bulletin/edition-1-halflfe-of-acting/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 04 Sep 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/bulletin/edition-1-halflfe-of-acting/</guid>
      <description>Nah but actually The Intern was ok.

Sidenote: If you’re technically inclined, head over to the lab to read this article with full source code in-line.
Much analysis has been completed regarding the performing peak of athletes and sportspeople.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Stratton</title>
      <link>/shiny/stratton/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 30 Jul 2017 10:26:46 +1000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/shiny/stratton/</guid>
      <description>Details Stratton interfaces three different film data sources (IMDB, Rotten Tomatoes, and Box Office Mojo) to provide a filmography + metadata for an actor or director of your choice. Use the analytics functionality in the app (charting, loess regression and kmeans clustering) to uncover an interesting story about an actor or director - much like the 538 article it was inspired by.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Under Construction</title>
      <link>/bulletin/edition-2-tbd/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 30 Jul 2017 10:26:46 +1000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/bulletin/edition-2-tbd/</guid>
      <description>Overview I told you not to look in here.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Under Construction</title>
      <link>/shiny/tbd/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 30 Jul 2017 10:26:46 +1000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/shiny/tbd/</guid>
      <description>Details Mate I told you it was under developments. Don&amp;rsquo;t look in here please.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>